for those who prefer Linux or are simply
对于那些喜欢Linux或简单的人来说
curious about Linux and other
好奇Linux和其他
open-source technologies this is
这是开源技术
category 5 technology TVs
5类技术电视
welcome to episode number 295 hi honey
欢迎来到第295集嗨，亲爱的
I'm home of category five technology TV
我是第五 类 科技电视的家
great to see ya it's Tuesday the 14th of
很高兴看到你是星期二的十四号
May 2013 295 episodes in Wow
2013年5月295集在 Wow
you're old were five weeks away from the
你已经五个星期 了
300 votes happy birthday we mentioned it
我们提到过300票生日快乐
on the air I know you were sitting at
在空气中我知道你是坐在
home watch and probably had a popcorn
家用手表，可能还有爆米花
actually sorry kids but I wasn't oh yeah
实际上对不起 孩子，但我不是噢
you weren't my daughter no I was
你不是我的女儿，我不是
expecting when she said dad my boyfriend
当 她说我爸爸是我的男朋友的时候
and I are gonna make dinner for you yeah
我会为你 做晚餐 是的
so I was all that Robbie already for
所以我就是罗比已经拥有的
Crafton and hot dogs sweet wit chicken
Crafton 和 热狗 甜美 机智的鸡
cordon bleu with audibles pasta and they
警戒线与audibles面食和他们
made a cake
做了一个蛋糕
wow it was freaking her in the president
哇，这 让她在总统中 感到 害怕
you were spoiled buddy I was here this
你被宠坏了， 我在这里
forum let's fix that you mention that
论坛让我们来解决这个问题 ，你提到
all they can hear is your beer well well
他们所能听到的是你的 啤酒 也很好
it's a good beer I had a good birthday
这是一个很棒的啤酒，我有一个美好的生日
while you're thinking of you Safin I
而你在想你 Safin 我
thought it would be guys too yeah geez I
认为这将是你们太 耶 吉兹我
could have been there instead of having
本来可以在那里， 而不是有
this chicken cordon bleu and I know that
这个鸡的警戒线， 我知道
was really sweet
真的很好
sorry speaking of birthdays next week is
抱歉说下周的生日是
Mauro Mauro
毛罗莫罗
we're hanging around til midnight and
我们游逛直到午夜
we're gonna we're gonna celebrate
我们要去庆祝
Rachel shoot big birthday tonight at
瑞秋拍摄大生日 在 今晚
midnight
午夜
yeah so happy birthday to our good
是的， 我们的 生日很开心
friend Rachel Shue
朋友Rachel Shue
so send in all the gifts and presents
所以送出所有的礼物和礼物
yards address them to me any checks made
码 向我解决任何检查
payable to earth yeah well what do you
支付给地球是啊，你是什么
think it's birthday season what do you
认为这是 生日季节 你有什么
got coming up did I tell them what's
得到了上来， 我才告诉他们什么是
coming up and you love to know love to
即将到来，你爱去了解爱情
know well coming up in the newsroom
很 高兴在新闻编辑室出现
YouTube has launched a trial scheme for
YouTube已经 启动了一项试用计划
paid channels on its website the
付费频道在其网站上
International Space Station is
国际空间站是
jettisoning windows in favor of linen
抛弃窗户而转向亚麻布
hmm IBM has opened a new center in China
惠普IBM 在中国 开设了一个新的 中心
built exclusively to code applications
专门为代码应用程序构建
for Linux and 25 of Scotland's busiest
对于Linux 和苏格兰最繁忙的25个
railway stations will soon offer free
火车站将很快提供免费
Wi-Fi access courtesy of the Scottish
Wi-Fi接入由苏格兰人提供
Government okay cool
政府 好凉快
stick around these stories are coming up
坚持这些故事即将到来
later in the show it is retro gaming
后来在展会上 它是 复古 游戏
month here at category-five TV if you
如果你有五个月的电视节目，那么这个月将会是
haven't done it already get over to our
还没有做到这一点， 已经交给我们了
website category 5 press up left right
网站类别5向左上 移
down and ya down here you go I'm
下来， 你在这里，你去我是
literally I'm this little flying thing
从字面上我是这个小飞行的事情
because it is
因为它是
well that's me that's me adding the
那就是我，那就是我加入的
sound effects but you know that as you
音效，但你知道，因为 你
do this you will be you'll be doing the
做到这一点，你会做你会做的
same you'll be going the kids will be
同样你会去孩子们会
lady what are you doing the wife is what
小姐，你在做什么，妻子是什么
is what's come on I'm just having some
是怎么回事，我只是有一些
retro gaming action fun here my love
复古游戏动作乐趣在这里我的爱
that's what we do a category 5 TV now
这就是我们现在做的第5类电视
this is pretty much your last chance
这几乎 是你最后的机会
because retro gaming month is actually
因为复古游戏月份实际上是
almost over if you can believe it
如果你 能相信的话，几乎可以结束
I do retro gaming all the time I play ya
我一直玩复古游戏， 我玩雅
know 3 pitch softball pretty old clock
知道3球垒球漂亮的 老钟
and skates and realize yeah you get hurt
并溜冰，意识到你受伤了
and I haven't break-in I recall the
我还没有 磨合我记得
story we'll leave that alone
我们将 独自 离开
yeah so that's that's what we're doing
是的，这就是我们正在做的
on our website for retro gaming month
在我们的网站上进行复古游戏月
we've had a lot of fun stuff going on
我们有很多有趣的事情在进行
here on the show you remember if you if
这里 就告诉 你记住，如果你要是
you didn't catch it in you're into retro
你没有接受它，你陷入了复古
gaming check out episode number 292
游戏结账第292集
where we're Erica and myself actually
这里我们埃里卡和我 实际
sat down with a colecovision tonight
今晚坐下来参加 一次联合电视会议
straight out of 1982 that was awesome
直出 的1982年，这是真棒
but also to celebrate retro gaming month
也是 为了庆祝复古博彩月
we're gonna go over to google.com CA
我们要去投奔 到google.com CA
last week we were showing you how to use
上周我们向您展示如何 使用
Google Image Search and all this kind of
谷歌图片搜索和所有这类
stuff so we're gonna show you a little
所以我们会 告诉 你一点
easter egg here tonight on Google's
今天晚上在谷歌的 复活节彩蛋
website so we're
网站，所以我们
go Tuesday yeah let's go to the image
去星期二是的，让我们去 图像
search and in keeping with our theme of
搜索和保持我们的主题
retro gaming we're gonna do a quick
复古游戏我们会做一个快速的
search on images ok so we're on Google
在图片上搜索好，所以我们在 Google上
Images for Atari breakout there we go
Atari的图片在那里爆发
there's our image search
有我们的图片搜索
go for it everybody head on over to
去了大家 随手打开
Google Images and do a search for Atari
Google图片并搜索 Atari
breakout for a little more nostalgic
突破一点怀旧
gaming action oh my I also got a great
游戏动作 哦， 我也很棒
email from Al Peck one of our wonderful
来自Al Peck的电子邮件是我们的 精彩之一
viewers who directed us also over to the
观众谁指示我们也 到了
Atari site I can actually I'm gonna
雅达利网站其实我可以我 会
punch this into my browser I've written
把它写入我写过的 浏览器中
it down here so ww8 re comm slash arcade
它在这里 如此ww8 re通斜杠街机
slash I love how it's still going
斜线我很喜欢它仍然如此
no slash actually after arcade
拱廊 后没有真正的斜线
crunchbang so that's the hash
crunchbang所以这是哈希
explanation mark ok slash arcade slash
解释标记 确定斜线街机 斜线
Atari
雅达利
- promo and if I did that right there we
- 促销，如果我那样做， 我们
go we're actually going to be able to
去我们实际上将能够
load up the Atari arcade and get some
加载雅达利街机， 并获得一些
more yes some more retro gaming action
更多的是一些更复古的游戏行动
and like Missile Command
并像导弹命令一样
well pong super breakout yars revenge
乒乓超级突围 洋人复仇
asteroids asteroids centipede don't
小行星 小行星蜈蚣 没有
worry folks you don't have to remember
担心你不必记住的人
that verbatim I will actually I'm gonna
这个逐字我 实际上我 会去的
copy and paste that in the chat room
复制并 粘贴到聊天室中
right now pardon me and that's done and
现在请 原谅我，那已经完成了
I'm also going to post a link for you in
我还打算在 张贴链接 ，你
the show notes of episode number 295 or
第295集或第295集的节目注释
such a good guy
这样一个好人
we love our retro gaming what can I say
我们喜欢我们的复古游戏，我可以说什么
so tonight we're actually gonna be
所以今晚我们真的会这样
looking at Apache web server logs and
看着Apache Web服务器日志和
how we can actually monitor our web
我们如何才能真正监控我们的网络
server we're gonna have a little fun
服务器，我们会有一点乐趣
with it though not only are we gonna
与它虽然不仅我们 会
show you some productive ways to do it
告诉你一些有效的方法来做到这一点
but we're gonna actually convert your
但我们会转换你的
Apache logs into a game of classic pong
Apache登录到经典乒乓 游戏 中
so you'll be able to actually see those
所以你将能够真正看到这些
pings happening back and forth in a game
乒乓球在游戏中来回发生
of pong so stick around don't go
乒乓球如此坚持不走
anywhere
随地
this is category five technology TV and
这是 第五 类 技术电视和
yeah gonna be a fun show
是的，会 是一个有趣的节目
I've got your viewer questions and I'm
我有你的观众问题，我是
already having fun you already whoa
已经有 乐趣，你已经 哇
tonight's show as you know is brought to
今晚的节目，你知道带到
you in part by ads irk ads are calm is
你部分受到广告irk 广告冷静是
the next generation my eyes are open
下一代我的眼睛是开放的
ad-serving yep
广告服务是的
I don't look at my abs er come on okay
我不看我的腹肌呃加油好吗
come on people
来吧 人
all right with ads er calm if we got a
如果我们得到了一个，那么 广告就可以保持 冷静
website you can actually monetize it by
网站实际上可以通过它获利
generating the world's fastest
创造世界上最快的
asynchronous JavaScript ad serving code
异步JavaScript 广告投放代码
go over to ads err calm to find out more
去找广告，再 冷静地找出更多
get your free account and sign up today
获得免费帐户并立即注册
also our mobile site is up and run and
也是 我们的移动网站投入运行，
go to m dot cat v dot TV there you go
去到m点组织Cat V点电视 你去那里
Eric's got his Blackberry you always
Eric的得到了他的黑莓手机 ，你 总是
tell me to turn my wireless off I know I
告诉我关掉我的无线电我知道我
didn't before we sat down does that
没以前我们坐 了下来 确实是
thing work with anything other than
事情与 其他 任何事情一起工作
Wireless these days oh yeah right lots
无线这些天 哦适合很多
going on at though in the world of
虽然 在 在世界 上发生
blackberry isn't there there's lots
黑莓不在那里 有很多
going on yeah yeah how's that working
继续 耶耶是如何 工作
it's been great yeah yeah good that's
这是伟大的耶耶是好的
good I still love my Canadian product
好， 我仍然 爱我的加拿大产品
Aeolus pronounces Archie oldest given
风神 发音阿尔奇最古老的给出
blackberry old call me love yeah well he
黑莓老叫我爱 耶 以及他
had a blackberry for two months in a
一个黑莓已经有两个月了
proq hey they're not submergible they
proq嘿他们不能淹没他们
you know they're not good in toilets
你知道他们不擅长洗手间
apparently either my friend drop one in
显然无论是我的朋友放下一个
there and not some you're not
在那里，而不是一些你不是
submergible it doesn't matter but the
潜水也没关系， 但
lady not swim well I'm gonna give you a
女士不会游泳好我会给你一个
copy of that oh great because we're we
那 很棒的副本， 因为我们是我们
need to I want to know what we're
需要我想知道我们是什么
brought to you there Eric yeah okay ring
带给你那 里埃里克耶 没关系响
I do not see where it says there right
我没有看到它说的是对的
there there yeah mobile site M account
那里有 移动网站 M帐户
five dot TV Robbie right oh there's this
这是五 点电视 罗比吧
home there graph right here Eric hey
那里的家在那里图 埃里克嘿
category five dot TV
五类点电视
a member of the tech podcast network if
科技播客网络的成员如果
it's tech it's here and the
它的技术在这里和那里
international association of internet
国际互联网协会
broadcasts thanks Eric
广播感谢Eric
Eric welcome back to the show welcome
埃里克欢迎 回到表演 欢迎
back to earth
回到地球
hey buddy Chris Hatfield is back on I
嘿伙计克里斯哈特菲尔德 回到我身上
saw he landed safely fantastic indeed
看到他确实安全地降落了
and you know he's probably the most
你知道他可能是最多的
exciting astronaut they think that's
他们认为这是令人兴奋的宇航员
ever been up there definitely the most
永远在那里肯定 是最多的
tech-savvy and and musical and now you
技术精湛和音乐， 现在你
know I yeah I had had a great jam
知道我是，我有一个伟大的果酱
session with he and his brother and
与他和他的兄弟和
about 20 other people and I devote
约20 个人和我投入
several years ago and and he's actually
几年前，而且他其实是
quite a good musician it was fun it was
相当优秀的音乐家，这很有趣
fun and he I think he kind of had fun
有趣，他 我觉得他很有趣
the fact that people were asking him how
人们 问他如何 的事实
a song went instead of can you tell me
一首歌不是 你能告诉我吗？
about the Space Shuttle yeah right we
关于航天飞机 是 对的我们
had a great night it was we are great
有一个伟大的夜晚， 这是我们 伟大的
they call yeah that's gonna happen back
他们 称是啊 ，这要发生的事 回
here on e pluribus unum I want to say
在这里， 我想说
welcome to our new registered viewers on
欢迎来到我们的新注册观众
our website this month or this week I
我们的网站本月或本周我
should say pardon me we've got I'm gonna
应该说原谅 我，我 已经得到了我 要去
give it my best folks
给它我 最好的人
that's their name nice to see ya thanks
这是他们的名字很高兴看到你的 感谢
for being here is that like a like a one
因为在这里 就像 一个人一样
of those laughs like there it is welcome
那些喜欢那里的笑声是值得欢迎的
so that's exactly it
所以 就是 这样
can L can Klingon Lemuria no Lemuria
L 可以克林贡Lemuria没有Lemuria
nizam you know welcome to the show and
nizam你知道 欢迎 来到节目和
Gible Dean Ferrara welcome so much to
Gible Dean Ferrara对此非常欢迎
the show nice to have you here you're so
该节目很高兴有你在这里，你是如此
much welcome Eric touched on a very
非常欢迎埃里克一个非常感动
important note tonight it was a nice
今晚的重要记录这是一个很好的
something that we we want to thank Roga
我们想要感谢 Roga
harvey on that on twitter at Roga harvey
Harvey 在 Roga harvey的 Twitter 上 发表了 这个观点
for for pointing us in this direction
为了指引我们朝这个方向发展
Bing had a big announcement this week
Bing本周发布了一个重要消息
today
今天
yeah Bing a big you ready big bean baby
是的，一个大你准备好 大豆宝贝
now Z are you ready for this now you
现在Z你准备好了，现在你
touched on this a little bit earlier and
谈到这个有点 早 ，
so I just want to kind of okay segue
所以我只想要种好的赛格
into this okay so we're gonna translate
进入这个好，所以我们要翻译
from
从
auto-detect but we're gonna translate to
自动检测， 但我们要翻译成
okay we're looking at bing.com slash
好的，我们正在看bing.com 斜线
translator this is the Bing Translator
翻译这是 必应翻译
and we know that okay google translate
我们知道，谷歌翻译好
we're not so keen on right now because
我们现在不那么热衷，因为
they decided they're gonna charge us $40
他们决定他们会向我们 收取40美元
every time we want to use it I mean here
我们每次想要 使用 它，我的意思都是在这里
we are translating or putting books into
我们正在 翻译 或放入书籍
their reCAPTCHA system for them and and
他们和他们的reCAPTCHA系统
this is how they thank us well so that
这就是他们如此感谢我们
defines us over on bing.com slash
在bing.com斜杠上定义我们
translate whore not translate this is
翻译妓女不翻译这是
the Bing translate or okay it's an
必应翻译或好吧，这是一个
important step in the right direction
向正确 方向迈出重要的一步
for technology because for the first
因为第一个技术
time ever on bing.com slash translate or
时间 在bing.com斜线翻译或
we can translate to Klingon this is this
我们可以把这个翻译成克林贡
is new today folks so okay let's let's
今天是新的人，所以好吧，让我们来
give it a go
搏一搏
WW category-five TV let's translate that
WW类别五电视让我们来翻译一下
to Klingon
到克林贡
oh we're live oh that is scary
哦，我们活着 哦，这是可怕的
Vlad Chuck left iPhone Cub and iPod
Vlad Chuck离开了iPhone Cub和 iPod
users hot users guys congratulations
用户热门家伙祝贺
Russian to go along with the Condor yeah
俄罗斯与 秃鹰是 一起去的
it's kind of appropriate under test new
在 新的 测试中它是合适的
platforms shock and just in case you're
平台震动 ，以防 万一
wondering II young or you dong Vlad ja
想知道II 年轻还是你的Vlad ja
papa pug kill you on email or email em
爸爸帕格 杀死你的电子邮件或 电子邮件
all who really knows I love that the
所有真正知道我爱的人
menu is even tray translated I mean if
菜单甚至托盘翻译 我的意思是如果
you want to you can interact
你想要你可以互动
very impressed with Microsoft for the
对于微软来说非常感动
first time ever
有史以来第一次
that's a bit harsh you know they finally
你知道他们终于有点苛刻了
have built a technology I know you're a
已经建立了一项我知道你是一个技术
bill basher but they have finally the
比尔巴赫尔，但他们终于了
technology that
技术
we we okay we owe you I appreciate and
我们我们很好，我们欠你我欣赏和
can utilize and it's gonna make
可以利用，它会做出
everybody want to install the Bing
每个人都想安装必应
Translator app in their mobile device so
在他们的移动设备中翻译应用程序如此
that when you go to the convention you
当你去参加大会 时
know it's easy enough to to punch it in
知道很容易就可以冲进去
like where d NL s went to translate but
就像d NL去 翻译的地方一样
that's exactly how you set it by them
这正是他们 如何 设定的
alright okay all right guys we've got to
好的， 好吧， 我们必须要的 所有 正确的人
take a real quick break on that note we
采取 关于这一点，我们 真正的快速突破
will be right back don't go anywhere
将马上回来 不要去 任何地方
at eco alkaline z' we believe you should
在生态碱z我们相信你应该
be able to trust your batteries not just
不仅能够信任 你的电池
here but here here and here but with one
这里， 但在这里，在这里， 但 有一个
exception you should also be able to
异常你也应该能够
trust your batteries here eco alkaline
相信 你的电池在这里 生态碱性
zuv the world's first and only certified
zuv是世界上第一个 也是唯一一个获得认证的
carbon neutral battery manufactured to
碳中性电池制造
the highest standards of recycling and
回收的最高标准，
quality without any trace amounts of
质量没有任何痕量的
harmful chemicals like mercury lead or
有害的化学物质， 如汞铅或汞
cadmium Eco outlines provide performance
镉Eco概述提供性能
the rivals leading national alkaline
领先全国碱性的竞争对手
battery brands at a comparable price
可比价格的电池品牌
find out more about the Eco alkaline
了解 更多关于生态碱
difference Eco alkaline calm
区别生态碱性 冷静
this is category 5 technology TV I'm
这是我的第5类技术电视
your host Rob a Ferguson and I am
你的主人Rob a Ferguson和我在一起
co-host well you read the most hi I'm
共同主持好， 你读最喜欢我
Erik kid with no small Nick Nick that
埃里克小子 尼克尼克那个 不小
means welcome back I'm impressed with
意味着欢迎回来， 我印象深刻
you yes you know very good I am a geek
你是的，你知道很好， 我 是 一个怪胎
some way back yeah all right or to quote
有些回头 耶是好的或引用
young Rachel nerdling nerdling I can I
年轻的瑞秋书呆子 书呆子我可以
can believe that I can believe that
可以相信我可以相信这一点
yes all right so Erik you you've had
是的，所有的 Erik你都有
experience running Apache lamp stacks
体验Apache 灯栈
and running server Eisen one of the
并运行服务器Eisen之一
things that can be difficult or
事情可能很难或
challenging is trying to track down if
具有挑战性的是试图追查是否
you know if you're getting a whole lot
你知道你是否得到了 很多
of traffic and you're wondering what's
的交通和你想知道什么
actually going on maybe you're under
实际上， 也许你在下
some form of a dass attack or somebody's
某种形式的dass攻击或某人的形式
you know running a script that's
你知道运行一个脚本
accessing your site over and over and
一遍又一遍访问您的网站
over again something along those lines
再次 沿着这些线路
so your server logs all of a sudden
所以你的服务器一下子记录下来
become really really helpful but also
变得真的很有帮助，但也
server logs are kind of fun to watch
服务器日志看起来很有趣
because it helps you to understand how
因为它可以帮助你理解如何
people are using your website for me
人们 正在为我使用您的网站
helps me to see if maybe I've got some
帮助我 看看，也许 我有一些
dead links throughout the site maybe I'm
也许我是整个网站的死链接
still linking to some old content we've
仍然链接到我们已有的一些旧内容
been around for you know we're in our
一直在为你知道我们在我们的身边
sixth year here and so it's very
第六年 在这里，所以非常
possible after 295 episodes that we've
可能在295集之后，我们已经
had some files and and pages on our
我们有一些文件和页面
website that have fallen by the wayside
网站 已倒在路边
and then sometimes I forget so then all
然后有时我会忘记一切
of a sudden I look at the server logs
突然之间我看着服务器日志
and I see oh here's all my 404s and I
我看到哦， 这里是 我所有的404和我
know that those files need to be either
知道这些文件需要 是
redirected with htaccess or whatever I
重定向htaccess或任何我
need to do or maybe lose the link or
需要 做什么或可能失去 链接或
delete the link all together or purge it
一起删除链接 或清除 链接
from Google or whatever I need to do so
从谷歌 或任何我 需 要这样做
tonight we're gonna look at three
今晚我们要看三个
different tools one of them is not so
其中不同的工具 其中之一 并非 如此
useful but a lot of fun one of them is
其中很有趣，但其中一个很有趣
going to be a really helpful way for you
要 成为 你的 真正有用的方法
to be able to look at your existing
能够 看看你 现有的
Apache logs and the third is actually
Apache日志和第三个 实际上是
going to allow us to monitor our server
要允许我们 监视我们的 服务器
in real time which is exceptional for
实时，这是例外
you know if you're under a DDoS attack
你知道你是否受到DDoS攻击
or something like that somebody's
或者是 某人的 东西
hacking away at your server and you want
侵入你的服务器和你想要的
to figure out hey what's actually going
弄清楚究竟是怎么回事
on here why if I got such a high CPU
在 这里为什么如果我有这么高的CPU
usage on my Apache processes so
在我的Apache进程中的用法如此
everything that we want to look at is
我们想看的所有东西都是
available directly through apt-get so
可以直接通过apt-get获得
it's a part of debian so if you're on a
它是debian的一部分， 所以如果你使用的是
debian based system via to boon to
基于debian的 系统通过以实现
server boon to desktop or debian itself
服务器福音台式机或Debian系统
I'm on point Linux for example which is
例如，我在Linux上的点
Debian 7 so any of those you'll be able
Debian 7， 所以你可以做任何事情
to install these directly from packages
直接从软件包 安装
but you can also do that with whatever
但你也可以用它来做到这一点
distribution that you're using so let's
您使用的是分布的，以便让我们
take a quick look all right I'm gonna
快点看看我会去的
jump into my terminal and you'll see
跳进我的终端 ，你会看到
that what I've actually done what have
那我实际上做了什么
you done Lottie well let's see okay so
你完成了Lottie 让我们看看 好吧
I've got two files there Apache one dot
我在那里有两个文件Apache 一个 点
log and Apache two log I knew that we
日志和Apache 两个日志 我知道我们
were gonna be doing this presentation so
会这样做 这个演讲
I actually created a couple of really
我确实创造了一些
quick fake Apache logs oh so these just
快速假阿帕奇日志 哦， 所以这些只是
give us some some logs to work with so
给我们一些日志来处理
if I actually open this and please
如果我真的打开这个，请
you can see that I've generated random
你可以看到我已经随机产生了
fake IP addresses and made it look like
假IP地址，并使其看起来像
an Apache log and it is in every essence
一个Apache日志，它在每一个本质
in Apache log but it's just fake
在Apache日志中， 但它只是假的
generated information so that we're not
生成的信息， 所以我们不是
revealing anyone's private info here on
揭示任何人的私人信息
the show so the first tool that we want
这个节目是我们想要 的第一个工具
to look at because again it's nostalgic
看看，因为它再次怀旧
gaming month so here at category five TV
游戏月在这里 五类 电视
you know it's our first priority to make
你知道这是我们的首要任务
sure that you find interesting nostalgic
当然 ，你会 发现有趣的怀旧
gaming ways to interact with your server
游戏方式与您的服务器进行交互
logs and speaking of nostalgia the
日志和讲话的怀旧之情
application that we're gonna look at
应用程序，我们要看看
tonight first and foremost is called log
今晚首先是被称为日志
stal juh so all we need to do to get
stal juh所以我们需要 做的就是获得
that I'll just because I'm in a pseudo
那 我就 因为我是 一个伪
based system that's not as easy at all
基础的系统， 不是 那么容易 的
apt-get install and we're gonna go log
apt-get install，我们要去登录
stal Gaea just like that and then enter
Stal Gaea 就是这样， 然后 进入
your password and you'll see that I've
你的密码，你会看到我的
already got the latest version installed
已经安装了最新版本
but that's going to just install blog
但是这只是安装博客
stal juh so now with my Apache log I've
stal juh现在用我的Apache日志
got Apache dot one dot log for example
例如，获得了Apache点的一个点日志
I'll use that one so we're gonna do a
我会用那个， 所以我们会做一个
couple of things first of all now that
首先现在是几件事情
that's installed log stal Gaea - - help
这是安装 日志stal Gaea  -   - 帮助
is gonna give you a bunch of information
会给你一些 信息
about what we can do you see that it is
关于我们能做什么你 看到它是
you know it's pretty verbose you can set
你知道 它 可以设置很详细
the window size and go fullscreen if you
窗口大小， 如果你去全屏
want and all the different settings so
想要和所有不同的设置
real quick what I'm gonna do with this
真正快速的我会用这个做什么
log stal Gaea and a couple things that I
日志stal Gaea 和 我 的一些 事情
want to do is I want to change the glow
想做的事就是我要 改变辉光
intensity what do you see a dr.
你看到什么博士？
Beaudette yeah I'm gonna make it a
Beaudette是的，我会成为 一个
little bit brighter all right we're
我们是一 点点光明
gonna go glow duration and we're gonna
会发光持续时间，我们会去的
set that to say one second so that it
设置说一秒钟以便 它
lasts a little see where I'm getting
持续一点，看看我在哪里
this information okay see this is from
这个信息 没关系看到这是 来自
the dash - help so he's only using the
破折号 - 帮助， 所以他只用 了
bottom two or three because he can't see
底部两三个， 因为他看不到
up higher yeah I can I can scroll up
更高耶是我可以向上滚动
though focus I can scroll up
虽然 焦点 我可以向上滚动
okay so glow duration one and we're
好吧，发光持续时间一天，我们就是
gonna go grow multiplier see that grow
要成长倍增看到增长
- multiplier and we're gonna set that to
-乘法器和我们要设置到
something high like three all right yot
像三人一样高的事情都 很好
thinks you should be brighter for longer
认为你应该更明亮一些
than one second you think you can manage
你认为你可以管理的时间超过一秒钟
that for a while
那一段时间
well this is a pretty active server log
以及这是一个非常活跃的服务器日志
right so you know I want you to be
对，所以你知道我想让你成为
brighter you can play along play around
光明，你可以沿着发挥作用 的 发挥
with these settings notice - s4 now
现在 注意这些设置- s4
obviously I know that setting that's
显然我知道那是设置
just the speed the default is one which
只是默认 的 速度是 一个
is gonna be and I don't see it there
会是，我不会 在那里 看到 它
it's up here somewhere oh there it is
它在这里某处哦，它是
speed
速度
okay so default is one I'm gonna set it
好，所以默认是我要设置它
to four just so that things move a
到四个只是 让事情移动一个
little bit faster because we're talking
因为 我们正在交谈， 所以 速度稍快
a game of pong here it's got to be
乒乓这里的游戏就一定是
interesting it's got to be fun and now
有趣的是它现在 变得很有趣
we need to tell it okay where is our log
我们需要告诉它 我们的日志 在哪里
so I'm gonna type Apache dot one dot log
所以我要输入Apache dot一个点日志
or you can you know if you're on your
或者你可以知道你是否在你身边
server you've got access to it by SSH
你可以通过SSH访问它
you can go VAR log Apache to access dot
你可以去VAR日志Apache访问点
for example okay in my case I've just
例如 我的 情况 好吧 ，我 刚刚
got this thing on my desktop that we're
在我的桌面上找到 了我们的 东西
using for the sake of the demonstration
为演示而使用
and so what we're doing is we're gonna
所以我们正在做的是我们会
actually take that Apache log and we're
实际上采取了这个Apache日志，我们是
gonna turn it into a very useful display
将它 变成一个非常 有用的显示
are you ready for this this is fun hit
你准备好了吗？这很有趣
enter
输入
Oh what did I do wrong option unknown
哦，我做错了什么选择 不明
grow multiplier Oh grow its glow sorry
成长倍增哦发光 对不起
folks
乡亲
yeah glow multiplier and check to grow
是的辉光倍增 和检查成长
your intelligence there we go there's my
你的智慧我们去那里是我的
server log and so what's happening on
服务器日志以及发生了什么事情
the left is these are the IP addresses
左边是这些是IP地址
and they are hitting the server at these
他们正在 这些 服务器 上
files and the paddle is moving back and
文件和桨板向后移动
forth just like a game of pong or no can
就像一场乒乓球或不可以的比赛一样
you move the pillars it doing enough no
你移动 它 的 支柱足够没有
it's too it's it's reading the log and
它也是它 读取日志和
it's simply saying okay this person is
这只是说这个人好
loading episode 292 ping and it's going
加载情节292平和它的
back and forth and it's showing the file
来回 ，它的显示文件
being sent the request being sent to the
被发送的请求被发送给
server and the file being sent back to
服务器和文件被发送回
the user right how cool is that so it's
用户权限如何的酷是， 所以它的
just it's just like that break out Atari
就像是 打破 Atari一样
breakout application we're looking at on
我们正在研究的突破性应用程序
go that's very cool whatever then it's
去那是 非常酷的一切那么它的
true this is the most useless
这 是最 没用的
application ever but why is it that I
申请过，但为什么是我
love it you my nerdling friend
爱你我的书呆子朋友
speak Klingon qapla and that's been
说克林贡卡普拉，这是一直
useful for you too hasn't it it doesn't
对 你也 很有用， 但事实并非如此
have to be useful if you like it come on
如果你喜欢它，必须有用
chocolatey mmm yeah what he said
巧克力嗯，他说的是
there you go did he swear up it's
你去那里他才 发誓了 它的
happened so that's a visualization of my
发生了，所以这是我的可视化
log files like I said it's absolutely
日志文件就像我说的那样绝对
useless as far as anything other than
没用就比 其他任何
just it looks pretty it looks at all
它看起来很漂亮
looks pretty behind me so the desert
看起来很像我身后的沙漠
cool glow yeah well that's why I set up
凉爽焕发很好啊，这就是为什么我设置 了
the the grow the girl oh that was never
那个永远不会成长的女孩哦
mind no there you go yes okay so then we
不要在那里，你去是的，那么我们
need to okay obviously that's that's not
需要很好，但事实并非如此
a use useful tool it's just kind of fun
一个有用的 工具，它只是一种乐趣
we want to actually be able to monitor
我们希望实际上 能够 监控
all right and look at our server logs
好吧，看看我们的服务器日志
and figure out okay what's actually
并确定什么是实际
happening on our server so let's close
发生在我们的服务器上 ，让我们关闭
that down and don't only go play my
那下来，不仅要 去玩我的
blaze of glory just like that okay
就像那样好的荣耀之光
so next tool that I might want to look
所以我可能要看的下一个工具
at is really really helpful it's called
这真的很有帮助，这就是所谓的
go access and again it's available in
去访问，并再次可用
your app get repositories app get go
你的应用程序会得到存储库应用程序
install go access like that okay not
安装去那样的访问没关系
necessarily all typed in in that order
必须 按照该顺序输入
but mine set already the newest version
但我的设置已经是最新版本
well you saw what I typed oh yeah I know
以及你看到我输入的内容哦，我知道
apt-get install go access and if you're
apt-get install去访问，如果你是
on Debian pure Debian you would instead
在Debian纯Debian上，你会改为
go s you enter enter your root password
去你输入你的root密码
so that you're a super user and then
所以， 你是 一个超级用户，然后
just type apt-get install go access no
只需键入apt-get install go access no
need for the sudo right because you're
因为你需要sudo
then su din okay so with go access this
然后su din好吧，然后去访问这个
is a different can of worms altogether
是一个完全不同的蠕虫罐头
it's not for fun this is for
它不是为了好玩，这 是为
functionality so but a can of worms
功能如此，但 一罐蠕虫
could be fun okay there you go
可以很有趣好吧，你去
go access dash F is the command but
去访问破折号F是命令， 但
again you can go - - help oh no I guess
再次，你可以去 -   - 帮助哦，不，我猜
you can't just type go access and there
你不能只键入去访问那里
you go you do receive some help you'll
你走你得到一些 帮助 ，你会
see that this one is not as verbose but
看到这个 不是冗长的，而是
it does prompt you for the file and a
它会提示你输入 文件和a
couple other little things but so in our
再加上其他一些小东西， 但在我们这里
case we're just going to go access
我们只是要去 访问
- f and then Apache dot-to-dot log I'm
-  f，然后是Apache 点对点日志
just gonna use that one because I have
只是要使用那个， 因为我有
some referrers and things that I've
一些推荐人和我的东西
added to that to that one solution yeah
补充说 那个 解决方案是的
so then when I run that now you notice
所以当我运行它时，你会注意到
that it's running in a terminal window
它在终端窗口中运行
okay so that's this one's text-based so
好了，这是这一个基于文本的 这样
this one works really really great on
这一个工程上真的很伟大
say a server excellent way to be able to
说服务器很好的方法， 能够
check out your Apache logs because it's
检查你的Apache日志，因为它
unusually so when I push - - F of course
当我 推 -   -  F当然是 异常 的
you might again take that and say var
你可能会再次接受 并说var
log Apache to access dot log all right
记录Apache访问 点日志 所有权利
could be that in our case we're just
可能是在我们的情况下，我们只是
gonna access this one okay and let's on
要访问这一个好，让我们继续
your desktop that one's just on my
你的桌面，只是我的
desktop yeah and I have C to the to the
桌面是啊，我有C到的
desktop okay so I can use my cursors I
桌面好，所以我可以使用我的游标我
like my up and down arrows to move
像我的上下箭头一样移动
around and you'll see a couple of things
你会看到 一些事情
here unique visitors per day one is
这里每天都有独特的访客
number one okay requested files is
第一个好的请求的文件是
number two requested static files is
第二个请求的静态文件是
number three so just to give you a real
第三，所以只是为了给你一个真实的
quick tutorial on how to use this I'm
关于 如何 使用这个我 快速教程
defaulted to number one so if I press o
拖欠第一，所以如果我按o
it's gonna open number one and then I
它会打开第一，然后我
press Q - to close that so see it's the
按Q - 关闭，看看它的
same as what's up there in the top under
一样什么事在有顶 下
number one it's the same kind of
第一，它是一样的
information but it's gonna give me
信息，但它 要给我
everything instead of just the top what
一切， 而不是只是顶部什么
is that five or six service so the
那五六个服务是这样的
number two is the requested file so all
第二个是所请求的文件
I have to do is press - and then the
我必须做的是按 - 然后
letter O so - oh and it's opened
字母O所以 - 哦，它被打开了
requested files and now I can actually
请求的文件，现在我可以 实际上
scroll through here and I can find out
在这里滚动，我可以找到
more information about what files are
有关哪些文件的更多信息
being requested how much bandwidth those
被请求多少带宽那些
are consuming and things like that
在消费类的东西
helpful helpful helpful right sorry hope
有用的帮助帮助 对不起希望
it shows me all the links on the website
它向 我 展示 了网站上的所有链接
and and how people are navigating the
以及人们如何 驾驶汽车
site or what files they're opening so I
网站或他们正在打开什么文件，所以我
can continue to scroll down and I can
可以继续向下滚动 ，我可以
look at okay what files are being
看看行不行 正在哪些文件
requested that are you know static files
要求你知道静态文件
so I press 300 and it gives me a list of
所以我按300，这让 我的列表
all the static files that are being
所有 正在存在 的静态 文件
opened and this can be helpful too to be
打开， 这也可以有帮助
able to find out you know if
能够发现你知道如果
being exploited because sometimes one of
因为有时候会被利用
the ways that you'll be you know someone
你会认识某人的方式
will attempt to exploit your server is
会试图 利用你的服务器
to try to open files on your server that
试图打开你的服务器上的文件
don't exist they might be looking for
不存在，他们可能正在寻找
files and so you might see them in there
文件，所以你可能会看到 他们 在那里
or you might see them in if we scroll
或者如果我们滚动，你可能会看到它们
down to number five you'll see 404
到 第五个，你会看到 404
responses which is not found so you see
没有找到答案，所以你看到
that okay I do have some that are
那好吧，我确实有一些
missing but you notice here that here
失踪， 但你在这里注意到这里
are some images that it's looking for
是它正在寻找的一些图像
but I don't have those images nor have I
但我没有这些 图像，也没有我
ever had those images and yet they're
曾经有过这些图像，但它们是
giving a 404 so it tells me that
给404一个这样告诉我
somebody is actually testing my server
有人正在测试我的服务器
to see if those files are there why
看看这些文件是否存在原因
would someone do that why would somebody
有人会这样做，为什么会有人
do this because they know say Joomla or
这样做是因为他们知道说Joomla或
WordPress or whatever they know the file
WordPress或任何他们知道该文件
structure the of the the application so
结构中的所述 应用程序 ， 从而
if somebody has WordPress installed you
如果有人安装了WordPress 你
pretty much know that there's gonna be a
几乎知道会有一个
wp-content folder so you can kind of try
wp-content文件夹，所以你可以尝试
that folder to find out if this person
该文件夹来查明这个人
is running WordPress or in Joomla it
正在 运行的WordPress或 它的Joomla
might be you know a certain file within
可能你是在知道某个文件
Joomla or whatever application it is
Joomla或其他任何应用程序
because they know how those you know the
因为他们知道你是如何知道这些的
file structure so whatever ad underscore
文件结构，所以无论广告下划线
gray underscore pins ping is that file
灰色的下划线引脚是该文件
is a part of something that they're
是 他们 的东西的一部分
testing for and the reason they would
测试 和他们会的原因
test for that is they might know that
为此测试是他们可能知道的
okay well this particular application
好吧，这个 特殊的应用程序
has an exploit that would allow me to
有一个漏洞，可以让我
exploit this server so that now point me
利用这个服务器 ，现在指向 我
to okay well maybe now I need to grep
好吧，也许现在我需要grep
through my log for ad underscore gray
通过我的日志广告下划线灰色
underscore pins find the IP address of
下划线引脚找到的IP地址
who it is that's trying to access this
这是谁试图 访问这个
file that doesn't exist because they're
文件不存在，因为它们是
obviously trying to do something and
显然想要 做点什么
then block that IP with IP tables for
然后使用IP 表格阻止该IP
example right so that's that's a couple
例如，这是一 对夫妇
of the options that we can use that for
的选项， 我们可以利用 它 来 进行
so you can scroll around through here up
所以你可以 在这里 滚动 浏览
and down it gives you everything from IP
并向下 它给你从IP的一切
addresses that are accessing the server
正在访问的服务器地址
status codes on your server and again
您的服务器 上 的 状态代码 和再次
you just press the number that is
你只需按数字即可
associated with it so if I just press
与之相关， 所以如果我只是按下
nine oh it's going to give me all the
九哦，它会给我所有 的
status codes for example and then we
例如状态码，然后我们
press Q and that closes
按Q 以及 封闭
the window that's open because it's all
因为这一切而开放的窗口
done within the the terminal right one
在终端内完成正确的一个
little thing that might be a problem for
这件事可能 是一个问题
you is because let's say you know for
你是因为我们说你知道
example I'm running this through a
例如我正在 通过一个
terminal and terminal emulator on a GUI
终端和终端模拟器 在GUI上
so I'm not actually really at the
所以我其实并没有真正在这方面
terminal I'm running it through this
终端我通过这个运行它
right main terminal so if I want to
所以如果我想
press f1 for example it doesn't do
按f1 例如它不这样做
anything but you see that f1 is supposed
除了你看到的那个f1都是假设的
to be help
帮助
so that and okay now it's brought up
所以，现在好起来了
mate terminal health well that's no good
队友终端的健康状况并不好
to me but that's how that's what's gonna
对我来说， 但那就是这是怎么回事
happen right because you see f1 is
发生的权利，因为你看到F1是
actually allocated to contents for mate
实际分配给配偶的内容
terminal so what we'll actually do is
终端， 所以我们实际上做的是
we're gonna push that super user button
我们会推动那个超级用户按钮
which is the the window key I don't know
这是我不 知道 的窗口键
if you can see that Heather but the it
如果你能看到 希瑟，但它
usually looks like a window key on your
通常看起来 像你的窗口键
keyboard so if we hold that button in
键盘， 所以如果我们拿着那个按钮
within the terminal and then we press
在 终端内，然后我们按
the f1 key now you'll see what's gonna
f1键现在你会看到会发生什么
happen is a lot different it actually
发生的事实上 有很大的不同
brings up the terminal based help so now
所以现在带来了基于终端的帮助
I've got a way to actually send the
我有一种方法可以实际发送
keystrokes
击键
even though typically I wouldn't be able
即使通常我不能
to do that so that can be very very
这样做可以非常非常
helpful just to know that little tidbit
有用的 只是知道这个小 珍闻
because maybe you want to get access to
因为也许你想访问
the help maybe you want to be able to
也许你希望 能够帮助
that sometimes I found there was another
有时我发现有另一个
reason that I had to press during the
我 在这期间 不得不按的理由
setup I had to press like f10 something
设置 我不得不按F10的东西
like that which brings up the file menu
就像那个调出文件菜单一样
and in the application I think so that
而在 应用我想， 这样
just makes it a lot easier so that is go
只是让它变得容易很多， 所以就这样走了
access pretty cool QQ to quit and then
访问非常酷的QQ退出 然后
the final tool that I want to look at
最终的工具，我想看看
tonight you're gonna love this one
今晚 你会喜欢这个
modularly love this one you're gonna
模块化地喜欢这一个你会
love this one is the ability to actually
爱这个人 其实 是一种 能力
monitor your server in real time this is
监控您的实时服务器，这是
where it gets fun so get ready to bring
在那里玩得开心，所以 准备好带来
up our site get ready just have a sip of
我们的网站准备就绪， 只需一口
my coffee there okay the next tool I
我的咖啡 好吧，下一个工具 我
want to look at is called Apache top now
现在想 看看现在叫做Apache的顶端
you've all heard of top and H top and
你都听说过top和H top和
all those kind of tools
所有这些工具
well Apache top is kind of a similar
以及Apache的顶部是怎样的 一个 类似 的
tool for monitoring your Apache logs so
工具来监控你的Apache日志
sudo apt-get install Apache top
sudo apt-get安装Apache的顶端
enter you'll see I've already installed
输入你会看到我 已经安装
it I've got the newest version oh no I
我有最新版本哦，不，我
haven't installed it falling bug we
没有安装它 下降的错误我们
removed yeah yeah yeah watch your wallet
删除 耶耶耶是 看你的钱包
can do what is it gonna remove well I
可以做什么它会去除我很好
don't know I'm gonna say no to zero I
不知道我会说我不是零
know why that is because I'm running
知道为什么那是因为我在 跑步
this on my local computer I don't have a
这在我的本地计算机上我没有
patchy install on my on my computer here
在我的计算机 上 在我的补丁安装
so instead what I'm gonna do is I'm
所以相反 ，我要做的是我
actually gonna I'm gonna remote into my
实际上我会远程进入我的
server and we're not gonna mention any
服务器，我们 不会提到 任何
of this stuff on there how I'm accessing
这些东西在那里我如何访问
the server or anything deal I didn't see
服务器或任何 我没有看到的 交易
you you didn't see me we didn't see a
你没有看到我，我们没有看到
thing
事情
all right let's get access here okay
好的，让我们在这里访问
there okay so on my server what we're
那里好了 ，所以我的 服务器 上 就是我们
gonna do is okay like I was showing you
要做就好，就像我向你展示的那样
and this is a Debian server so I'm
这是一个 Debian服务器，所以 我是
actually I su to get here so I don't
实际上我总是来这里，所以 我不 这样 做
need to do sudo so apt-get install and
需要做sudo apt-get install和
we're gonna go Apache top and here
我们要去Apache的顶端和这里
you'll notice that yes I already do have
你会注意到， 我已经有
in fact have the newest version so now
实际上现在 有 最新版本
what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna go Apache
我要做的是我要去阿帕奇
top - Q and actually let's again start
顶部 - Q实际上让我们再次开始
with - - help so you know what I'm
- 帮助你知道我是什么
actually doing so hello mean right
其实这样做 打招呼的意思是正确的
okay so there's how you get your help so
好了，还有，你如何让你的帮助 ，所以
- Q is gonna keep query strings just so
- Q是要继续查询字符串 只是如此
that they stay up on the screen and so
他们保持在屏幕上 等等
we're gonna go Apache top - Q - T and
我们要去Apache的顶端 -  Q  -  T和
it's an uppercase T for the time that
这是一个大写字母T的时间
you want to hold things I'll just put in
你想 抓住我 刚刚放入的 东西
3600 not sure if that's yeah seconds so
3600不知道这是否是秒
it just gives us a little extra time so
它只是给了我们一点 额外的 时间
they don't fly off the screen and then -
他们不会飞离屏幕 然后 -
F and then your file location so that
F然后你的文件位置，以便
might be for your bar hundreds log yeah
可能 是你的酒吧数百日志是啊
what's that like 10 minutes or yeah so
什么是10分钟或是 这样
VAR log Apache - whatever I'm actually
VAR日志Apache - 无论我实际上
gonna point this to my live server log
将这个指向我的实时服务器日志
so again we're not going to show that on
所以我们再也不打算表明这一点
the screen just for
屏幕只是 为了
confidential confidentiality reasons
机密保密原因
there we go okay so with that now it's
那我们现在 就好了
loaded up what looks like a top it's a
加载了什么看起来像一个顶部它是一个
bit like a top kind of layout we can see
有点像我们可以看到的顶级布局
how many requests there are and what's
有多少请求和什么
going on how much bandwidth we're using
继续使用我们正在使用的带宽
so everybody go hit our website category
所以每个人都去打我们的网站类别
five dot TV and what we're gonna
五点电视 和我们要去的地方
actually start to see here if you want
实际上开始看到 这里，如果你想
to bring that up and post a job if you
如果你愿意，可以提出并发布一份工作
can post a link in the show notes or in
可以在演出笔记或中发布链接
the chat log chat room there people can
聊天记录聊天室里 有人可以
click on it you'll see there are three
点击它你会看到 有三个
people there just hit the upper you know
那里的人只是碰到你知道的鞋帮
the slash so the first page and all that
第一页 和所有的斜线
you know so there's some more people
你知道，所以还有更多的 人
somebody logging in so I can actually
有人登录，所以我可以实际上
monitor this in real time and I'm seeing
实时监控并看到
ok how many processes what's going on
确定有 多少进程正在进行
we've got 29 requests going on right now
我们现在有29个请求正在进行
it shows us how much you know how many
它向我们 展示了多少你 知道 多少
resources were using how much memory how
资源正在 使用多少内存如何
much bandwidth per second and there are
每秒有很多带宽，还有
the files that are actually open hello
实际打开 hello的文件
Ravi f would have given a 404 but hello
拉维夫本可以给404但你好
everybody's hitting on some some weird
每个人都有些奇怪
files deserve yeah over here yeah what's
文件 应该 在这里 耶是什么
that so you'll see now if I actually
那么你现在就会看到，如果我真的
bring up our website I'm gonna I'm gonna
调出我们的 网站 我要去
actually participate in this and if you
实际上参与 这个，如果你
watch those logs I'm gonna go to
看着我 要去的那些日志
interact ask a question and if we watch
互动问一个问题，如果我们看
over here you're gonna instantly see
在这里，你会立即看到
somebody's clicked on ask a question
有人点了一个问题
there at the bottom so how many does
在底部有多少呢
that so anywhere that you click it's
在任何地方 你点击它
actually going to log that on my screen
实际上会记录 在我的屏幕上
so it's a real-time way to be able to
所以这是一种实时的方式
monitor it and I was mentioning at the
监控它， 我在提及
top of the show that this is a great way
节目的顶部，这是一个伟大的方式
to be able to figure out what's going on
能够弄清楚发生 了什么
if you're under attack and the reason
如果你受到攻击 和原因
for that is you can start to see that
为此 你可以开始看到这一点
what's happening you'll see here that
发生什么事你会在这里看到
right now somebody is opening several
现在有人打开了几个
files here's one for example
这里的 文件 就是一个例子
let's see here if I I do that sometimes
让我们看看这里 有没有这样做
I hit control-c which closes where I
我打了控制-c关闭我的地方
tweeted that you don't want to hear
啾啾说你不想听到
you'll see yeah it's over the clown the
你会看到它是对小丑的
deserted the who is it and that's why I
抛弃这个人，这就是为什么我
and I keep doing that okay let's so now
我继续这样做 行不行 咱们所以现在
let's actually go to I want to see if
我们真的去 看看 我是否 想看
this actually exists and you'll see that
这实际上存在 ，你会看到
there's somebody is hitting this page
有人正在点击此页面
over and over again postcard map and
一遍又一遍 明信片地图 和
it's not found that doesn't exist on my
没有发现它不存在于我的
server and there's other stuff that you
服务器，还有 你 的其他东西
know sometimes you'll see that people
有时知道你会看到 那些人
are trying to hit files and so you
正试图打击文件，所以你
wonder okay well what's going on there
好奇好，那里发生了什么事
and then you can dig a little deeper and
然后你可以挖 得更深一点
in fact on the weekend I had some really
实际上在周末我真的有一些
really weird things happening because I
真奇怪的事情发生， 因为我
saw that in my logs people were actually
在我的 日志中看到人们确实是
loading other websites so I started
加载其他 网站， 所以我开始了
seeing outside websites coming up in my
看到外面的网站出现在我的
server log and okay well that's not
服务器日志， 好吧，不是
possible because everything's relative
可能 因为一切都是相对的
right so you see as people are opening
对，所以你看到 人们开放
files I've got slash ask a question
文件我有斜线问一个 问题
slash articles list for example so for
例如斜杠文章列表
me to suddenly start seeing HTTP colon
我突然开始看到HTTP冒号
slash slash in that website and some
在该网站和一些斜线斜杠
kind of weird code there I realize okay
那种奇怪的代码我意识到没问题
somebody's trying to do something here
有人试图在 这里 做点什么
on my server so I looked a little bit
在我的服务器上，所以我看起来有点
deeper and I realized oh they're
更深 ，我意识到 他们是
actually using a backdoor and Apache
实际上使用后门和Apache
which is allowing them to proxy their
这是让他们代理他们的
way through my server and be able to
通过我的服务器方式能够
make requests so instantly lock that
请求立即锁定
down and got that fixed because you know
下来，并得到修复，因为你知道
you don't want that coffee is cold is
你不想那咖啡是冷 的
that Eric yeah so that's that's a you
埃里克是啊，所以这就是你
know really cool tool I'm loving being
知道真正很酷的工具，我很喜欢
able to use Apache top it's a really
能够使用Apache的顶端，这是一个真正的
cool way to just add a glance leave your
很酷的方式只是添加一目了然离开你的
server log up and running and you want
服务器登录和运行，你想要的
to set up permissions on your Apache
在你的 Apache 上设置权限
access log and be able to be able to
访问日志，并能能够
access it without being super user for
访问它而不是超级用户
example but you are a super user yeah
例如，但你是一个超级用户 是的
and there's wood wood chuck chuck is
并且有木头木头夹头 是
woodchuck could chuck wood
土拨鼠 可以夹住木头
so that's that that's Apache top and as
所以这就是Apache的顶级和as
I mentioned we've looked at go access
我提到我们已经看过去访问
and log stal juh I hope that those are
和日志stal juh 我希望那些是
able to help you when you're
能帮助你，当你
administering your server looking at
管理你的服务器 看
your Apache logs trying to figure things
你的Apache日志试图弄清楚事情
out and you know you watch those locks
你知道你在看那些锁
I'm gonna notice over the next couple
我会注意到 下一对夫妇
days now and I know that you are gonna
天，现在我知道 你是要去
see some weird stuff maybe some really
看到一些奇怪的东西， 也许一些真的
weird stuff secret codes embedded
嵌入奇怪的东西秘密代码
through 404 links there you have it and
通过404链接你有它和
let's see if this works
让我们看看这是否有效
be up to now I don't know that didn't
到现在 为止 我不知道没有
work okay alright happy birthday Rachel
工作好吧好吧 生日快乐Rachel
how sweet okay alright thanks everybody
多么甜蜜好吧，谢谢大家
are we having fun yet are you ready for
是我们 高兴了 ，你 准备好了吗
the news I am ready are you ready oh
我准备好的消息准备好了哦
he's ready alright well here are the top
他准备好了， 这里是最好的
stories from the category 5 TV newsroom
来自 5 类 电视新闻室的 故事
awesome YouTube has launched the trial
真棒YouTube已经启动了试用版
scheme for paid channels on its website
在其网站上的付费频道计划
under the pilot program a small number
根据试点计划的 一小部分
of content makers will offer the
的内容制造商将提供
channels for subscriptions starting
订阅频道开始
around 99 cents a month these channel
这些频道 每月 大约99美分
will offer a free 14-day trial and many
将提供免费的14天试用和许多
will have discounted annual rates
将有折扣年率
although the initial 53 channel lineup
尽管最初的53频道阵容
is fairly niche one expert suggested the
一位专家 认为这 是相当有利 的
move might ultimately squeeze some
移动可能最终会挤压一些
smaller rivals out of the market YouTube
较小的竞争对手退出YouTube市场
which is owned by Google said the launch
这 是Google所拥有的发布
was part of an effort to enable content
是实现内容的努力的一部分
creators to earn revenue for their
创造者 为他们赚取收入
creativity which we can respect but what
我们可以尊重的创造力，但是什么
do you think would you pay ninety nine
你觉得你会付 九十九块钱吗？
cents a month to watch category 5 TV
一个月的美分收看5类电视
share your thoughts by emailing live at
通过电邮直播 分享您的 想法
category five TV it's an interesting
第五类电视 这是一个有趣的
thought because yeah I think everybody's
想因为 是的 ，我想每个人都
gotten used to YouTube being free you
习惯于YouTube免费的你
just go and you find what you want you
去吧， 你 找到你想要的 东西
watch it and it's always been free but
看它，它一直是免费的，但
what what happens if I mean for us I
如果我对 我们 意味着什么会发生什么
mean to give you the opposite
意思是给 你相反的
perspective I think you know to think
我认为你应该 思考
that you got to pay for YouTube is
你需要为YouTube付费
you know people are getting a little bit
你知道人们 变得有点儿了
you know upset about that they haven't
你知道他们没有
forced it on us or anything like that
迫使它在美国之类的东西
it's but it's it's becoming available so
不过它正在变得可用
if let's say you were to pay us a dollar
如果让我们说你要给我们一美元
a month so 25 cents an episode right
一个月这样一集25美分的权利
think about what a difference that would
想想有什么区别 那会
make to the quality of the show being
使 表演的质量
able to upgrade cameras being able to
能够升级相机能够
purchase what we need to make the show
购买我们需要做的演出
as good as it can possibly be we've got
尽可能好，我们有
a you know we'll probably get a
你知道我们可能会得到一个
coffeemaker that can go right next to
咖啡机，可以去 旁边
your nice one of those ones that you
你那些那些你的不错的一个
just like yeah cop in and they're just
就像 是 警察进来，他们只是
and it's done then they can't complain
然后完成，然后他们不能抱怨
about it what's more than that he's like
它 更 重要的是 比他就像
no I'll find something else to all find
不，我会找到别的 东西都找到
something to whine about yeah well back
东西抱怨耶以及回
to Chris actually we're not talking
对 克里斯而言，我们 并不是在说话
about Chris here both the International
关于克里斯这里既是 国际
Space Station is switching from Windows
空间站 正在从Windows切换
to Linux for functions which require
到Linux的功能需要
increased in-house control makes sense
增加内部控制是有道理的
the decision was made by Keith chavala
这一决定是 由Keith chavala 制造
of United Space Alliance a Nassau
联合太空联盟一个拿骚
contractor oversees the writing and
承包商监督写作和
integration of software for the space
软件集成 的 空间
stations laptop network the network is
网络是 笔记本电脑 的网络
used by astronauts on a daily basis for
宇航员每天使用
location information inventory control
位置信息库存控制
and multimedia web streaming their
和多媒体网络 的 流
little space concerts exactly mmm
小空间音乐会完全 嗯
ground control to Major Tom the network
地面控制到汤姆少校 的网络
is used by astronauts oh no Harry said
被宇航员使用哦， 哈利 没有 说
that tonight mr. Zavala says we migrated
那个今晚 先生。扎瓦拉说我们已经迁移了
key functions from Windows to Linux
从Windows到Linux的关键功能
because we needed an operating system
因为我们需要一个操作系统
that was stable and reliable one that
这 是稳定和可靠的 一个
would give us in host control so if we
如果我们能够控制我们的话
needed to patch adjust or adapt we could
需要补丁调整或适应我们可以
as well as laptops the humanoid robot
以及类人机器人的笔记本电脑
called a Robonaut is that like rubbing
所谓的Robonaut就像摩擦
on Robonaut right will also be running
在Robonaut 权利也将运行
Linux will be taking over some of the
Linux 将接管其中的一些
human astronauts responsibilities both
人类宇航员的责任
dangerous and mundane and can be
危险和世俗，可以
controlled from aboard the station can I
从车站控制我可以
look at that quote again I really like
再看看那个报价我真的很喜欢
that he this guy is the professional for
他这个 人是专业为
NASA contracted he says we migrated key
美国宇航局承包了他说我们已经移民了
functions from Windows to Linux
从Windows到 Linux的功能
because we needed an operating system
因为我们需要一个操作系统
that was stable and reliable that's a
这 是稳定和可靠的 ，这是一个
bit harsh that's a little bit daring to
有点刺耳 ，这是一个有点 大胆
say something like that publicly and
说公开的 和 类似的东西
when you're in that kind of a plea and
当你在那种 认罪 和
then we can say it we repeat we can say
那么我们可以说我们重复 我们可以说
I'm gonna claim that for my own we
我会要求，对于我自己 ，我们
switch to Linux from Windows because we
从 Windows 切换到Linux， 因为我们
wanted stability and no viruses and what
想要稳定性，没有病毒和什么
else
其他
I mean awesomeness is that is it a
我的意思 是 说 真棒就是这样
feature if you read the box of Linux
功能，如果你阅读Linux的框
with awesomeness actually be the feature
真棒是真正的功能
I don't know I think so
我不知道我 是这么认为的
some of the books IBM hmm International
IBM hmm International的一些书籍
Business Machines know IBM opened the
商业机器知道IBM打开了
center today for computing systems in
今天以计算机系统为中心
Beijing to help customers and outside
北京帮助客户和外界
software engineers develop business
软件工程师开展业务
applications for the open source Linux
应用程序的开源Linux
operating system nice the facility will
操作系统不错
aid creation of programs for Big Data
帮助创建大数据计划
cloud mobile and social business
云移动和社交业务
computing and represents a sizeable
计算和代表一个 相当大的
investment Colin Paris general manager
投资科林巴黎总经理
of IBM Power Systems said in an
IBM Power Systems在一份声明中表示
interview he declined to say how much
他的采访他拒绝说多少
the company spent or how many workers
该公司花费了多少工人
were employed IBM chief executive
被聘用为IBM首席执行官
officer Ginni Rometty is focusing on
官员Ginni Rometty 正在关注
profitable businesses including data
包括数据在内的盈利业务
analysis and cloud computing to maintain
分析和云计算 来维护
growth
发展
she said services that help customers
她说服务帮助客户
mind troves of information to make
介意 的信息troves 使
better decisions are the company's
更好的决策是公司的
biggest priority the Beijing Center is
北京 中心是 最大的优先事项
the company's first to focus on Linux
该公司的第一个专注于 Linux的
applications for IBM's Power Systems
IBM Power Systems的应用程序
brand servers the center will
品牌服务器的 中心将
collaborate with Linux distributors
与Linux分销商合作
distributors Red Hat and su se
经销商Red Hat和Su se
I always find it awesome when and sorry
我总是发现它真棒 时，抱歉
for having a logo more awesome I find it
因为我找到了更好 的 标志
more often when a commercial like a big
更多的时候， 当一个商业 像一个大
company backs Linux with a commercial
公司支持Linux与商业
stance you know
你知道的立场
canonical did it so now to here iBM is
canonical 做到了 ，现在到这里iBM是
doing software for business for Linux
为Linux开展业务软件
that's a big step I mean that's a good
这是一个很大的步骤， 我的意思是这是一个很好的
push for people who who think Linux is
推动那些认为Linux是的人
just for hobbyists well no it's not I
只为爱好者而已，不，这不是 我
don't people will say that because they
没有 人会说，因为他们
don't know
不知道
any better so very cool all right free
任何更好，所以非常酷 没事免费
Wi-Fi access is to be introduced at
Wi-Fi接入将 在2004年推出
twenty five of Scotland's busiest
苏格兰最繁忙的 二十五 人
railway stations by the middle of next
下一个中间的火车站
year the move is the latest stage in the
这一年的举措是最新的一个阶段
Scottish Government's plan to ensure
苏格兰政府的计划确保
travellers have free wireless internet
旅客可免费使用无线网络
across the rail network by 2019 Scott
到2019年 斯科特 穿过铁路网
Reil began introducing free access on
Reil开始引入免费访问
its flight ship Edinburgh to Glasgow
其飞行爱丁堡至格拉斯哥
route last year and is now being rolled
去年的路线， 现在正在 推出
out across express trains the Scottish
穿过特快列车苏格兰
Government has provided 250 thousand
政府 提供了 25 万
pounds to fit Wi-Fi at the stations
英镑 在车站适合Wi-Fi
that's some really heavy cabling that is
这是一些非常沉重的电缆 是
in the phone stores a category-5 dot TV
在手机中存储 一个 5类点 电视
newsroom slash newsroom the category 5
新闻室削减新闻室类别 5
dot TV newsroom was researched by Roy W
dot电视新闻室由Roy W研究
Nash and Heather Bailey Brown with
纳什和希瑟贝利布朗
contributions by our community of
我们社区的贡献
viewers if you have a news story you
观众，如果你有一个新闻 故事你
think is worthy of on-air mention email
认为是值得 的空中提及电子邮件
newsroom at category 5 TV for the
新闻室在5类电视上播出
category 5 dot TV news from American
来自 美国的 5类点电视 新闻
thanks Eric
感谢Eric
tonight's show is brought to you in part
今晚的节目是 部分 带给 你的
by net talk find out more about them at
通过网络谈话了解更多关于他们
camp 5 dot TV slash phone you can
你可以营5点电视斜杠手机
eliminate the need for a wireless
消除对无线的需求
wireless text plan from your cell phone
无线文字计划从 您的手机
provider you can upgrade your net talk
提供商你可以升级你的网络谈话
duo account with the net talk text plan
与净谈话文本计划的二人帐户
for unlimited text messaging to USA and
无限发送短信到美国和美国
Canada check out cap v dot TV slash
加拿大检查帽 v 点电视 斜线
phone and start saving money today also
并且今天也开始省钱
we still got Netflix as a sponsor here
我们仍然把Netflix 作为赞助商
at category 5 get it while it's hot you
在第5类获得它，而它是 热的你
get a free month at cap v dot TV slash
得到一个免费的一个月在帽 v点 电视斜线
Netflix and every time something
Netflix 和每一次
registers every time somebody registers
每次有人注册时注册
for that free account at Netflix they do
为他们在Netflix的免费帐户提供服务
support and they love category 5
支持，他们喜欢 5 类
technology TV what's not to love I know
技术电视什么是不爱我知道
I know
我知道
and what's the 3-month the Netflix there
那里是3个月 的Netflix
you go yeah free unlimited movies and
你去是免费的无限电影和
shows it's a no brainer all good cool
表明这绝对是一件不错的事情
all right uh I would like to point us to
没事呃 ， 我想 我们指向
we've got very little time for questions
我们很少有时间 提问
tonight so we'll grab you know we'll
今晚 所以我们会抓住你 知道我们会的
start with that question there okay well
与这个问题 有 好的开始很好
in fact
事实上
here is a question from Henry hey hey
这里是来自亨利嘿嘿的问题
hey guys hey I have finally decided to
嗨嘿， 我终于决定
pursue my goal and become a famous
追求自己的目标，成为一名有名的
youtuber my main ranks of famous
youtuber我主要的着名行列
youtubers uber isn't that like a potato
youtubers优步 是不是像马铃薯
sorry
抱歉
they're my main content is going to be
他们是 我的主要内容
tutorials okay for many different media
许多不同媒体的 教程都 可以 使用
programs little animated and real-time
程序几乎没有动画和实时
short films and of course gaming for the
短片，当然还有游戏
gaming side it was wondering if you
游戏方面，它想知道你是否
could recommend the best way you would
可以推荐你最好的方式
record off ps3 Wii and/or other console
记录下 ps3 Wii和/或其他控制台
systems okay I have fraps for my PC and
系统好吧，我有 我的 电脑 和
it works beautifully okay do I need to
它精美的作品没关系 ，我需要
buy an HD PVR or can I just somehow hook
购买高清PVR 或者我 可以以某种方式挂钩
them up to my PC thanks guys PS my mom
他们到我的 PC感谢家伙PS 我妈妈
has a Bailey Brown hey good to see ya
有一个贝利布朗嘿很高兴见到 你
okay I'm just checking real quick what
好吧，我只是快速检查 一下
we've got here at cat5 TV /bh because
我们在 cat5 TV / bh找到了这里， 因为
it's the best place to shop
这是购物的最佳地点
okay so fraps is a great software tool
好吧，fraps是一款出色的软件工具
to be able to capture DirectX enhanced
能够捕获DirectX增强
3d gaming in Windows well it looks like
Windows中的 3D游戏看起来很像
we phone oh that's not what we want so
我们打电话哦，那不是我们想要的
it's it's really cool because it allows
这是非常酷的，因为它允许
you to capture those windows games but
你 捕捉那些窗户游戏，但
what do you do when you got the ps3 you
当你得到ps3时，你会做什么
can get something like a Blackmagic
可以得到像Blackmagic一样的东西
intensity Pro but it's probably not
强度Pro， 但 它可能不是
ideal for you because it's designed for
非常适合你，因为它是专为你设计的
basically TV broadcasting so if the
基本上电视广播，所以如果
devices that you're plugging into it are
你插入 它的设备是
not too perfect spec you know like
不是太完美的规格，你知道
perfect HD for form-fitting video right
完美的高清形式适合视频权利
it's just gonna be a black screen that
它只是会是一个黑色的屏幕
makes sense so if the resolution is off
如果分辨率关闭，这是有意义的
a little bit or whatever I have found
一点点或者 我发现的 任何东西
the card okay so what you need
卡好，所以你需要什么
what you need is the avermedia Zed aver
你需要的是avermedia Zed aver
aver media I don't know avermedia it
平均媒体我不知道它的媒体
doesn't matter how I say it because let
不管我怎么说，因为让
me read this whatever let me read the
我阅读 这些无论让我看看
description from the back of the box and
从箱子后面的描述和
you'll realize it doesn't matter how we
你会意识到我们的方式并不重要
pronounce things stream now it's your
发音事物流现在它是您的
Showtime
开演时间
make yourself celebrity of the world
让自己成为世界的名人
that matters that matter stream your
重要的 是你的事情
gameplay and let the world see what you
游戏，让世界 看到你
can do join thousands of your kind and
可以加入成千上万的你的种类和
top the ranked avermedia Apple media
排名靠前的苹果媒体
blah blah blah doesn't really matter
等等等等等等都 无所谓
that you are working on I can I can now
你正在努力 ， 我 现在 可以 做到
is it on the box the reason that you
它在盒子上是你的原因吗？
want to go with this one is because it's
想要与这一个去是因为它
it's dirt cheap and it's gonna get you
它很便宜，它会帮你
compressed input from HDMI or component
来自HDMI 或组件的压缩输入
from your ps3 or whatever other device
从你的PS3或任何其他设备
and if the resolution sent to this is a
如果 发送给这个 决议 是一个
little bit off doesn't matter it will
有点过不要紧它会
still broadcast the video and just might
仍然播放视频，只是可能
have a black bar on the side or
在边上有一个黑条或者
something like that so it works better
类似的东西 ，所以 它 效果更好
for that kind of stuff check out the
为那种东西检查出来
minimum specs it's compatible with
与其兼容的最小规格
Windows 7 probably eight I don't know
Windows 7 大概八个我不知道
and I found it here and if you go to cat
我在这里发现它，如果你去猫
five dot TV /bh and I'm gonna give you
五点电视/ BH，我会给 你
the code for it let's see if this works
它的代码让我们看看这是否有效
a VM T V GB cast I think that's the one
一个 虚拟电视国歌演员 我认为这是一个
let's give it a try so I go to cap 5 TB
让我们试试看，结果我上限5 TB
/ ph super circle battles Ovaltine and
/ ph 超级 圈子战斗奥瓦廷 和
there we go yeah alright so click on it
在那里，我们走了好，所以 点击它
and it's only 114 bucks
只有114块钱
alright and B&amp;H is great so what's great
好吧，B＆H很棒， 所以很棒
about this it's compressed video so your
关于这是它的压缩视频，所以你的
computer doesn't have to be as killer in
电脑不一定要成为杀手锏
order to capture video that's important
为了捕捉重要的视频
because with the Blackmagic intensity
因为拥有Blackmagic的强度
Pro you're looking at uncompressed 1080p
亲你正在看未压缩的1080p
video so what you're getting
视频，所以你得到什么
is this stream of video that you have to
这 是 你 需要 的视频流
have such a powerful computer in order
有以如此强大的计算机
to encode and so it you know it's you've
编码，所以你知道它是你的
you've gotta upgrade everyday average
你必须升级 日常平均水平
bear yeah this one here has an onboard
熊是啊，这里有一个在船上
chip that compresses the video on its
芯片压缩的视频其
way into the computer so that what
进入计算机， 使什么
you're receiving in the computer is is
你在电脑中接收的是
still 1080p but it's compressed so it's
仍然是1080p，但它是压缩的， 所以它
much less data you don't have to process
更少的数据你不必处理
it on the CPU it's already processed in
它已经在CPU中处理了
the capture card so check that one out
采集卡，检查， 一出
I'll also see about posting a link in
我还会看到有关发布链接的信息
the show notes for episode number 295 so
第295集的节目注释如此
watch for that actual link and I will go
注意那个实际的联系，我会去的
directly to that product alright thank
直接 向该产品表示 感谢
you the question we got time for a
你的问题我们有时间 了
couple of questions all right
几个问题都 可以
did you want to direct me in a certain
你是否想指导我一定
direction no no I wanted to you know
方向不，我想让 你知道
that's that's silly but one of our
这是愚蠢的，但我们的 一个
volunteers so well here is one from meow
志愿者这么好这里是一个从喵
hey me huh hello Robbie hey I have a
嘿，我哈哈你好罗比 嘿，我有一个
problem with my computer I user and six
我的电脑 用户和六个问题
I cannot use mobile Internet Oh
我无法使用 移动 互联网哦
meaning USB flash for permanent root
这意味着永久根的USB闪存
password and when I type my own and that
密码，当我输入我自己的和 那个
the internet gives the wrong root
互联网给了错误的根
password oh dear where did I go wrong
密码哦亲爱的我哪里错了
this is a tough thing because I don't I
这是一件困难的事情， 因为我 不是
don't use Wi-Fi on I haven't used it is
不使用 Wi-Fi我没有使用它
it Zorin or is it Luzerne 6 hmm hmm I
它Zorin或是它 Luzerne 6 嗯嗯我
would suggest I'm going to have to
会建议我将不得不
suggest that you get into their forums
建议你进入 他们的论坛
and see if anyone there has had bad
并看看有没有人有坏
experience with it and can help you the
与IT经验， 可以帮助您
only thing you could try that I could
只有你可以尝试 我能做到的 事情
suggest with any application in Linux is
建议在 Linux中的任何应用程序 是
run the tool from your terminal so that
从终端运行该工具使
you can see what errors are being
你可以看到什么错误正在
generated so for example I don't know
生成所以例如我不知道
how to really demonstrate this because I
如何真正展现这一点，因为我
don't use wireless cards right so but if
不要使用无线卡，但如果
I have a tool that is you know say that
我有一个工具， 你知道这么说
it's my configuration editor right so if
这是我的 配置编辑器， 所以如果
you're using gnome I can right click and
你正在使用GNOME，我可以右键单击和
edit menus and we're just using
编辑菜单，我们正在使用
configuration editor as an example but
配置编辑器为例，但是
under system tools you see configuration
在系统工具下您可以看到配置
editor right click on it and hold in
编辑器右键点击它并保持
right click and let go on properties and
右键单击并放开属性 和
I can see that the tool is called mate
我可以看到这个工具被称为队友
conf - editor in this example so
conf这个例子编辑器如此
go into terminal and I'm gonna type in
进入终端，我要输入
mate that conf - editor and that's going
队友编辑和即将到来
to open that tool but now if anything
打开 该工具，但现在如果有的话
goes bad
坏了
with this tool or there's an error it's
使用该工具或有这是一个错误
actually gonna spew out the error in my
实际上会发现我的错误
terminal so let's make it lay bare yeah
终端，让我们让它躺在床上
I wish I knew how with a mate competitor
我希望我知道如何与队友竞争
but that might point in a direction
但这可能会指向一个方向
because then you're gonna have some kind
因为那样你会有某种感觉
of output from the application itself so
来自应用程序本身的输出
you just have to find out what the
你只需要找出什么
executive will is to run sorry I can't
行政长官会抱歉，我不能
be more help there but hopefully the
在那里有更多的帮助，但希望 是
forums for for Zorin OS will be of help
Zorin OS的论坛将会有所帮助
to you I need to give up but I don't
对 你 我需要放弃，但我 不需要
know much about me I don't use it here
对我很了解我不在 这里使用它
but Robert from Melbourne Australia is
但墨尔本澳大利亚的罗伯特是
here and another question here all right
这里和另一个问题 在这里好吧
hi Robbie and Eric I have just switched
嗨， 罗比和 埃里克 我 刚换了
over to point Linux and have had a few
指向Linux 并已有一些
issues which most of them I have managed
其中大部分是我管理的问题
to sort out great the one that I have
理清 我所拥有的 伟大
been unable to fix is how to get steam
一直无法解决的是如何获得蒸汽
working I have tried a few different
工作我尝试了一些不同的
methods that I have found on some
我已 在一些找到 的方法
websites without any luck any
网站没有 任何运气
suggestions or any viewers got steam
建议或者任何观众都会有热情
working under point Linux thanks hmm I
在Linux下工作， 谢谢嗯
haven't tried it yet do they make let me
还没有尝试过，但 他们让我
just quickly
只是很快
I'm guessing that you're on 64-bit
我猜你在使用64位
Robert is that the case are you on
罗伯特是你的情况
64-bit point Linux I'm not getting
64位点Linux我没有得到
anything in the chat room from Robert
罗伯特 在 聊天室里的任何事情
let us know hey are you out there
让我们知道你是否在外面
the architecture of Debian has changed
Debian的体系结构发生了变化
quite a bit in Debian 7 and that's part
在Debian 7中相当多，这是其中的一部分
of how we you know that's what point
我们如何知道这是 什么点
Linux is so and I'm I'm honestly still
Linux是如此，我仍然诚实
kind of learning my way around how that
样的学习我围绕如何呀
all works but maybe this would be a good
所有的作品， 但也许这将是一件好事
question maybe I could bring it up again
问题也许我可以再提起来
next week when I have a bit of time to
下周我有点时间
prepare an answer because I have run
准备一个答案， 因为我跑了
into it as well so can you let us know
也可以让我们知道
are you running the 64-bit is that what
你运行的是64位的是什么
the problem is I think that would be the
问题是我 认为这将是
the first thing that I would check and
我会 检查 的 第一件事
just watch out that you don't don't go
只要注意你不会不去
through old tutorials that are for
通过旧的教程是
Debian 6 right the command that we need
Debian 6 正确使用了我们需要的命令
to do is dpkg space - - ad -
要做的是dpkg 空间 -   - ad  -
architecture space i386 and then do an
架构空间i386 然后做一个
apt-get update I can post information
apt-get update 我可以发布信息
about that in the in the show notes for
关于在 中 展现笔记
episode number 295 basically command
第295集主要是指挥
looks like this and all it does is it
看起来像这样，它所做的就是它
adds the ability to to run those 32-bit
增加了运行这些32位的能力
binaries because remember and this is
二进制文件，因为记得，这是
why I think that your on 64-bit is that
为什么我认为你 的64位是这样的
steam is not available for 64-bit yet so
蒸汽 不适 用于64位
you've got to install the 32-bit version
你必须安装32位版本
so that can be a little bit of a problem
所以这 可能是 一个小 问题
because we're switching over see before
因为我们 之前 正在切换
we used to install the ia32 libs right
我们用来安装IA32库 权
to be able to get 32-bit access now we
我们现在 能够 获得32位访问权限
don't do it that way because it's an
不要这样做，因为它是 一个
newer way of doing things the
更新的做事方式
architecture has changed so I would try
架构已经改变，所以我会尝试
that and then go through the regular
这一点， 然后再通过常规
steps of installing the 32-bit program
安装32位程序的步骤
and it should work just fine
它应该工作得很好
how new is steam steam is pretty new I
我觉得蒸汽有多新
mean we were looking at on the show just
这意味着我们只是在看节目
you know a month or so ago so it is it
你知道一个月左右，所以就是这样
available for previous yes oh yeah but
可用于以前是哦，但是
Debian 7 and point Linux just came out
Debian 7和Point Linux刚刚问世
dead on 7 was stable on Saturdays
7日死亡在周六稳定
of Saturday of last week so so very very
上周六的星期六非常非常
knows a little own sample I know you
知道我 认识你 的一点自己的样本
know what can you do what can you do
知道你能做什么，你可以做什么
do we have that all right a short one
我们是否有 这么短的一个
thanks for the question Robert and if
感谢Robert和如果的问题
that helped if that just was the answer
如果那只是答案，那会有所帮助
then let us know but that's what I'm
然后让我们知道，但是 这就是 我什么
thinking anyway all right well let's see
无论如何思考好了让我们来看看
what do we have here
我们在这里有什么
I don't know what do this is a question
我不知道这是一个问题
the fur off air oh no that doesn't
皮毛停播 哦，不，一点 不
matter it doesn't matter thanks Robbie
无关紧要， 谢谢 罗比
good stuff he's not suppose that this
好 东西他不是这个
here's his IP address and here's his
这是 他的IP地址 ，这是 他的
email address so what else know what was
电子邮件地址，所以还有什么知道什么
Danny saying you said it doesn't matter
丹尼说你说的没关系
yeah no it doesn't matter that it says
没错，它说的没关系
it is for off air oh it doesn't know I
它是在空中哦，它不 知道我
think it does she sent him here now okay
想想看，她 现在 把他送到这里 了 吗？
thanks Robbie I got handbrake loaded and
谢谢罗比，我手里拿着手刹
it is working how much do I owe you
它正在工作多少钱我欠你
I'm so glad he ruined the joke anyways
无论如何，我很高兴他破坏了这个笑话
he's cool
他很酷
last week we were talking about
上周我们在谈论
handbrake on the air and our good friend
手刹在 空中和我们的好朋友
Danny had sent in the question when one
当一个 丹尼发过问题 时，
man and we were able to nail it and
男人，我们能够钉它 和
unfortunately I had some mic issues
不幸的是我 有一些话筒 问题
there at the end of the show glad you
在节目结束时，你很高兴
were able to make it out glad that it
能够让它感到高兴
was that it worked for you and if you'd
是它 为你工作 ，如果你愿意
like to donate his camp 5 TV slash see
喜欢捐出他的阵营 5电视剧 斜看
that was not a part of my script by no
这是不是 我的脚本的一部分 不
cat5 TV slash see if you want to throw
cat5 电视斜线看看你是否想扔
the the other error is spelled with the
在其他 错误拼写与
C yeah don't don't put it with a K cuz
C是啊，不要把它与 K cuz
it'll go to the wrong person
它会去错误的人
oh my well then that's all the time that
哦，我很好，那就是 那个时候
we have I think I am keep reading
我想我一直在阅读
questions yeah yep
问是啊
all right mics are gonna all of a sudden
所有正确的话筒 都会 突然出现
stop work and so they cut us off at 8
停止工作 ，所以他们在8点把我们关了
o'clock I mean YouTube is just like
我的意思是，YouTube 就像
that's it shut it down that's it yeah
这就是关闭它，就是这样
fun you like that actually YouTube said
有趣的是你喜欢 YouTube的说法
stick around I just got a message from
坚持围绕我刚 得到一个 消息
YouTube YouTube just said stick around
YouTube YouTube 刚刚表示坚持
we're gonna actually have
我们会真的有
hang out after the show hang out hang
演出结束后挂出挂出
out so if you've got your webcam handy
所以如果你有你的摄像头方便
stick around say hi we're gonna get Eric
坚持周围打个招呼， 我们会得到埃里克
another coffee
另一杯咖啡
last week was this birthday so this time
上周这个时候是这个生日
around it's gonna be a very special
这将是一个非常 特殊的
coffee first we're gonna hang out in the
首先我们要在咖啡厅闲逛
chat room and and in the Google Plus
聊天室和Google Plus中
hangout which you can find at cat5 dot
您可以在cat5点找到的环聊
TV / g + g PL us g+ and that's cat5 TV /
TV / g + g PL us g +这就是cat5 TV /
g plus category thank you
g加类别谢谢
hope you had fun just send us your
希望你玩得开心就把 你的
questions live at category-five dot TV
问题居于五类网点电视
is where you want to email us through
是你想通过电子邮件发送给我们的地方
the week and get your questions in and
本周，并 在 和 你的 问题
we appreciate that
我们欣赏这一点
don't forget chris is coming in next
不要忘记 克里斯将会进入下一个
week awesome that I always point out
我总是指出这一周真棒
she's she's way more charming and
她是她更迷人的方式
better-looking you like absolutely I
更好看 你喜欢我绝对
have to agree yeah see you have a great
不得不同意耶 看到你有一个伟大的
week bye bye bye
周再见再见
we hope you enjoyed the show category
我们希望你喜欢这个节目类别
five TV broadcasts live from Barrie
来自Barrie的五个电视节目现场直播
Ontario Canada every Tuesday at 7:00
加拿大安大略省， 每周二7:00
p.m. Eastern if you're watching this on
下午东部，如果你正在观看 这个
demand or through cable TV check out the
需求或通过有线电视检查出来
local show times in your area at at
在你所在地区的当地演出时间
aghori five TV and find out when
aghori五台 电视，并找出什么时候
community chat where
社区聊天在哪里
poverty digital solutions and his
贫困 数字解决方案和他的
lessons
教训
solution 2.5
解决方案2.5
thanks between them
感谢他们之间